

Irene Martín Menéndez

2 07548662369

https://www.linkedin.com/in/irene1martin2menendez

About me

After 4 years working in Finance across marketing and publishing sectors, I am ready for my next challenge: Becoming a Web Developer.

Before moving into Software Development, I worked in Accountancy where I was responsible to maintain the Management Accounts and posting journals to the correct ledger. I have developed attention to detail, math and problem solving thinking and other skills really useful for this new pivot in my life.

To get the knowledge, I have completed the Web development Bootcamp, I learnt all needed for a Full Stack Web Developer, as it teaches you to build complex server-side web application using:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, DOM, Node.js, APIs, Git and GitHub, EJS, SQL, MongoDB, Mongoose and React.js.

Also, I have created my own projects, you can check my portfolio here and contact me if you are interested!

Personal Projects

Portfolio	https://imartinmenendez.github.io/portfolio/	2021
Personal Blog	www.laultimapagina.com	2021
Memory Game	https://imartinmenendez.github.io/MemoryGame/#	2021
Web App	https://imartinmenendez.github.io/RelaxMe/#	2021

Education

Santander Tech | Digital Reskilling - Ironhack Scholarship (+60hr)

2021

Selected from 300 best candidates in attitude test to complete this Pre-Work Bootcamp.

Web Development Bootcamp. (+50hr)

2021

Udemy course prepare for a job as Full Stack Web Developer and teach you to build complex web applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React and MongoDB.

Degree in Administration and Business Management.

Present

National Distance Education University.

International Commerce and Economics Management.

2015

Professional certificate. (INEM, Oviedo)

Work experience

Management Accountant Assistant

2020 - April 2021

Thames & Hudson Limited

Using Sage X3 and Excel to assist in the preparation of the management accounts, review and investigate variances, produce and reconcile eBooks sales reports, assist with X3 sales journals upload, maintain fixed assets register, post depreciation journals, reconcile monthly balance sheets for key accounts, posting management fees, accruals, prepayments and payroll, raising recharge invoices, creating COS invoices and send them to the subsidiaries, create journals to post sales, calculate royalties and accrued COS, updating cash balance books, updating staff purchase to deduct in the payroll, credit card checking and posting.

Billings Coordinator

March 2018 - Jan 2020

Hogarth Worldwide Limited

Using Maconomy program to review and approve new jobs ready for billing, raising invoices and credit notes for intercompany and direct clients, using portals and other means to ensure clients receive their invoices in good time, finding efficient working to ensure deadlines are met, understanding audits requirements and ensuring all departments follow with SOX compliance, review the open jobs report and taking action to reduce the work in process, working collaboratively with the credit control team to resolve queries.

Assistant Accountant / Executive Assistant - Finance

March 2017 - March 2018

Cobra Group of Companies

Accountant Using Excel (VLOOKUP, Pivot table) and Microsoft Dynamics AX program to process Purchase Ledger, Sales Ledger, Credit Note, Credit control, Expenses claim and Credit Card Expenses, weekly Payment Run, posting cash, Bank and Reconciliation, Intercompany, Companies Houses (annual return, dormant accounts), National and International Recharges, Filing documentation, some knowledge of Cash Flow and Month End.

Executive Assistant

Translating phone calls (from Spain and Brazil), Planning Agenda, Travel organization, Manager Expenses Claim.

Manager Waitress

2016 - 2017

Retro Café (London)

Opening and closing the café. Teaching and guiding the new members of the team and explaining them about the job. Responsible of keeping track of the daily gaining. Doing the best to provide a good service to the customers.

International commerce technician - Internship

2015

Norvil (Gijón-Spain)

Packing list creation, customers billing and invoicing, origin control certificates. Used F-Moda's software to do the inventory of the merchandise available.

2012 - 2016 Waitress

El Gato con Botas Coffee Shop (Oviedo-Spain)

Treat with customers, sale of products, store control, closing the coffee, and count the cash. Attend customers, prepare and serve all kind of coffees, keep the coffee shop in good conditions, taking card and cash payments. Cooked Spanish tapas.

Administrative Assistant.

2007 - 2011

Magalia restaurant (Ávila-Spain)

Preparing bills, documents control, attending customers and suppliers, doing the orders to buy, paying the employees, stock control.

Languages

Spanish, English, Portuguese (Basic)

Computing

- o Word, Excel and PowerPoint specialist (Certification MOS specialist, 2015)
- Certification expert MOS Word and Excel. (2015)
- Microsoft Outlook.
- o Microsoft Dynamics.

Other

- Red Cross volunteer (Oviedo Spain)
- o I wrote and published a novel.